<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Space Quest</title><link href="https://spacequest.uk/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://spacequest.uk/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://spacequest.uk/</id><updated>2023-11-16T10:20:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Asteroid</title><link href="https://spacequest.uk/asteroid.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-11-16T10:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-11-16T10:20:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Edward Gomez</name></author><id>tag:spacequest.uk,2023-11-16:/asteroid.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Asteroids are pieces of rock, metal and frozen gases left over from when the planets in our Solar System formed. Most of the asteroids orbit around the Sun between Mars and Jupiter in a large loop, called the Asteroid Belt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Occasionally an asteroid will stray away from this path and …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Asteroids are pieces of rock, metal and frozen gases left over from when the planets in our Solar System formed. Most of the asteroids orbit around the Sun between Mars and Jupiter in a large loop, called the Asteroid Belt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Occasionally an asteroid will stray away from this path and head towards the Sun. This can bring it close to Mercury, Venus, Earth and Mars. Astronomers monitor "Near Earth Asteroids" to check whether any of them will come very close to Earth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shooting stars, or meteors, are made from small pieces of asteroids which have broken off. They burn when they hit Earth's atmosphere giving them their distinctive glow. A small number of the largest meteors do not burn up and land on Earth, sometimes forming a crater. After they have collided with Earth they are called meteorites.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="articles"></category></entry><entry><title>Black Hole</title><link href="https://spacequest.uk/black-hole.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-11-16T10:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-11-16T10:20:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Edward Gomez</name></author><id>tag:spacequest.uk,2023-11-16:/black-hole.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Black holes are mysterious things. Astronomers believe that a supermassive black hole is at the centre of every galaxy, but are not sure how they got there. Smaller black holes are made when big stars (much bigger and hotter than our Sun) explode at the end of their lives. The …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Black holes are mysterious things. Astronomers believe that a supermassive black hole is at the centre of every galaxy, but are not sure how they got there. Smaller black holes are made when big stars (much bigger and hotter than our Sun) explode at the end of their lives. The intense explosion squashes all the gas from the very centre of the star into such a dense ball that not even light can escape its gravity. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
It is a misconception that black holes will gobble up everything in their path. Their gravitational pull is only deadly if you get too close. Further away, their gravitational pull will work in the same way as anything with the same mass. The point where this switch happens is called the Event Horizon.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="articles"></category></entry><entry><title>Comet</title><link href="https://spacequest.uk/comet.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-11-16T10:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-11-16T10:20:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Edward Gomez</name></author><id>tag:spacequest.uk,2023-11-16:/comet.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Comets are similar to asteroids with one key difference - they have tails. They are made up of rock and metal, like asteroids, but with much more frozen gases. When comets travel close to the Sun, the heat from the Sun melts these frozen gases and small particles of cosmic dust …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Comets are similar to asteroids with one key difference - they have tails. They are made up of rock and metal, like asteroids, but with much more frozen gases. When comets travel close to the Sun, the heat from the Sun melts these frozen gases and small particles of cosmic dust leaving a tail behind them. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Comets are the frozen remains of the gas and dust that the Solar System formed from. They are formed far away from the Sun and planets, in a bubble surrounding the Solar System called the Oort Cloud. Some comets are periodic, and they visit the Sun regularly. Others only head in towards the Sun once before returning to the outer Solar System forever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The particles of dust left behind by comets' tails float in space for a long time after the comet has gone. If the Earth's orbit crosses the path of a past comet, the dust burns up in the Earth's atmosphere. These events are called Meteor showers.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="articles"></category></entry><entry><title>Jupiter</title><link href="https://spacequest.uk/jupiter.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-11-16T10:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-11-16T10:20:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Edward Gomez</name></author><id>tag:spacequest.uk,2023-11-16:/jupiter.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Jupiter is the fifth planet from the Sun and the largest in the Solar System. It is a gas giant with a mass more than two and a half times that of all the other planets in the Solar System combined, and slightly less than one one-thousandth the mass of …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Jupiter is the fifth planet from the Sun and the largest in the Solar System. It is a gas giant with a mass more than two and a half times that of all the other planets in the Solar System combined, and slightly less than one one-thousandth the mass of the Sun. Jupiter is the third brightest natural object in the Earth's night sky after the Moon and Venus, and it has been observed since prehistoric times. It was named after Jupiter, the chief deity of ancient Roman religion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although Jupiter does not have a hard or rocky surface, it has a large oval feature, called the Great Red Spot. The Great Red Spot is a storm which has been raging for at least 350 years, and is big enough to fit 3 Earths inside.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="articles"></category></entry><entry><title>Mars Rover</title><link href="https://spacequest.uk/mars-rover.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-11-16T10:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-11-16T10:20:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Edward Gomez</name></author><id>tag:spacequest.uk,2023-11-16:/mars-rover.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;To explore our Solar System, humans always send machines before people. To send people to Mars would be much more expensive than sending probes and robots. Mars has had many robot visitors in the past and currently has 2 active robot cars or rovers on it. They have tools for …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;To explore our Solar System, humans always send machines before people. To send people to Mars would be much more expensive than sending probes and robots. Mars has had many robot visitors in the past and currently has 2 active robot cars or rovers on it. They have tools for investigating the ground and for digging and drilling underneath the surface. They  also have onboard mini laboratories for performing experiments.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="articles"></category></entry><entry><title>Moon</title><link href="https://spacequest.uk/moon.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-11-16T10:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-11-16T10:20:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Edward Gomez</name></author><id>tag:spacequest.uk,2023-11-16:/moon.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Moon is Earth's only natural satellite. It is the fifth largest satellite in the Solar System and the largest and most massive relative to its parent planet, with a diameter about one-quarter that of Earth (comparable to the width of Australia). The Moon is a planetary-mass object with a …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Moon is Earth's only natural satellite. It is the fifth largest satellite in the Solar System and the largest and most massive relative to its parent planet, with a diameter about one-quarter that of Earth (comparable to the width of Australia). The Moon is a planetary-mass object with a differentiated rocky body, making it a satellite planet under the geophysical definitions of the term and larger than all known dwarf planets of the Solar System. It lacks any significant atmosphere, hydrosphere, or magnetic field. Its surface gravity is about one-sixth of Earth's, with Jupiter's moon Io being the only satellite in the Solar System known to have a higher surface gravity and density.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="articles"></category></entry><entry><title>Saturn</title><link href="https://spacequest.uk/saturn.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-11-16T10:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-11-16T10:20:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Edward Gomez</name></author><id>tag:spacequest.uk,2023-11-16:/saturn.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Saturn is a gas giant, similar to the largest planet Jupiter, made of mostly Hydrogen and Helium gas. It does not have a solid surface or ground, although it most probably does have a rocky core.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Saturn has the most obvious rings of all the giant planets. Astronomers think these …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Saturn is a gas giant, similar to the largest planet Jupiter, made of mostly Hydrogen and Helium gas. It does not have a solid surface or ground, although it most probably does have a rocky core.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Saturn has the most obvious rings of all the giant planets. Astronomers think these were formed when the planets were formed. Moons inside the rings, called "shepherd" moons,  stop the rings forming into another moon or floating away.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="articles"></category></entry><entry><title>Space Telescope</title><link href="https://spacequest.uk/space-telescope.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-11-16T10:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-11-16T10:20:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Edward Gomez</name></author><id>tag:spacequest.uk,2023-11-16:/space-telescope.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Astronomers put telescopes in space so they can take better pictures of space, than we can on Earth.  Sometimes this is because they do not suffer from problems because of the weather. Sometimes this is because the Earth's atmosphere blocks different types of light. Because of this, space telescopes can …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Astronomers put telescopes in space so they can take better pictures of space, than we can on Earth.  Sometimes this is because they do not suffer from problems because of the weather. Sometimes this is because the Earth's atmosphere blocks different types of light. Because of this, space telescopes can help astronomers find things they never would have seen before.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="articles"></category></entry><entry><title>Spiral Galaxy</title><link href="https://spacequest.uk/spiral-galaxy.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-11-16T10:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-11-16T10:20:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Edward Gomez</name></author><id>tag:spacequest.uk,2023-11-16:/spiral-galaxy.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Spiral galaxies form a class of galaxy originally described by Edwin Hubble in his 1936 work The Realm of the Nebulae and, as such, form part of the Hubble sequence. Most spiral galaxies consist of a flat, rotating disk containing stars, gas and dust, and a central concentration of stars …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Spiral galaxies form a class of galaxy originally described by Edwin Hubble in his 1936 work The Realm of the Nebulae and, as such, form part of the Hubble sequence. Most spiral galaxies consist of a flat, rotating disk containing stars, gas and dust, and a central concentration of stars known as the bulge. These are often surrounded by a much fainter halo of stars, many of which reside in globular clusters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spiral galaxies are named by their spiral structures that extend from the center into the galactic disc. The spiral arms are sites of ongoing star formation and are brighter than the surrounding disc because of the young, hot OB stars that inhabit them.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="articles"></category></entry><entry><title>Star Cluster</title><link href="https://spacequest.uk/star-cluster.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-11-16T10:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-11-16T10:20:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Edward Gomez</name></author><id>tag:spacequest.uk,2023-11-16:/star-cluster.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Stars are born in groups, or clusters. When there is enough cosmic dust and gas in a cloud in space, its own gravity pulls towards the centre. When the centre gets hot and dense enough stars will form. These are star clusters and they contain a few tens to a …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Stars are born in groups, or clusters. When there is enough cosmic dust and gas in a cloud in space, its own gravity pulls towards the centre. When the centre gets hot and dense enough stars will form. These are star clusters and they contain a few tens to a few hundred stars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The stars are all different. Some big, hot and bright. Some, like our Sun, are yellow and moderately hot. Some are cooler and red. These stars all live for different lengths of time, but they are all the same age and all the same distance away from Earth.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="articles"></category></entry><entry><title>Sun</title><link href="https://spacequest.uk/sun.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-11-16T10:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-11-16T10:20:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Edward Gomez</name></author><id>tag:spacequest.uk,2023-11-16:/sun.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Sun is the star at the centre of the Solar System. It is a nearly perfect ball of hot plasma. It shines because of nuclear fusion reactions in its core. The Sun radiates this energy mainly as visible, ultraviolet, and infrared light, and is the most important source of …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Sun is the star at the centre of the Solar System. It is a nearly perfect ball of hot plasma. It shines because of nuclear fusion reactions in its core. The Sun radiates this energy mainly as visible, ultraviolet, and infrared light, and is the most important source of energy for life on Earth.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="articles"></category></entry><entry><title>Supernova Remnant</title><link href="https://spacequest.uk/supernova.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-11-16T10:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-11-16T10:20:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Edward Gomez</name></author><id>tag:spacequest.uk,2023-11-16:/supernova.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;At the end of their life hot and blue stars explode like cosmic fireworks, called supernovae or supernovas. When the fire which keeps the star looking like a ball burns through its fuel, the force of gravity pulls all the star in towards the centre. This happens so fast, that …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;At the end of their life hot and blue stars explode like cosmic fireworks, called supernovae or supernovas. When the fire which keeps the star looking like a ball burns through its fuel, the force of gravity pulls all the star in towards the centre. This happens so fast, that it has a drastic effect on the star. The very centre is crushed into a neutron star or a black hole. When this happens, the rest of the star bounces off the core, in a hot, bright explosion. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As time goes on, the insides of the star, which was made of hot gas, spreads into space like a ball-shaped cloud. This is the supernova remnant.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="articles"></category></entry></feed>